Inventory of the International Association for the Evaluation of Educational Achievement Records, 1959-1992
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence of people with the IEA, [requesting data /information etc] (Box 125)
- Final Publications - Reading Comprehension (Box 126)
- Reading Comprehension - subtests - populations I and 2 (Box 127)
- Literature - Population II - Item Analysis Sheets (Box 128)
- Reading Comprehension - Subtests (Box 129)
- Reading Comprehension - Subtests (Box 130)
- French as a Foreign Language - subtests (Box 131)
- Literature - Population II - Booklet 6 (Box 132)
- French as a Foreign Language (Box 133)
- French as a Foreign Language (Box 134)
- French as a Foreign Language (Box 135)
- French as a Foreign Language (Box 136)
- Literature (Box 137)
- Literature (Box 138)
- National Case Study Questionnaires (Box 139)
- English Literature (Box 140)
- Civic Education - Population IV - Subtests A,B,C (Box 141)
- English Literature- Population I, IV, IVS - Re-test WS - Collated Item Sheets (Box 142)
- English Literature- Population II - Subtest 1-6 (Box 143)
- Civic Education - Population II - Subtest A,B (Box 144)
- Science - Drawings (Box 145)
- English Literature (Box 146)
- Civic Education - Tests, Pretest form IVS, Draft of pretests (Box 147)
- Civic Education - Pretests (Box 148)
- All disciplines - Teacher Questionnaires, etc (Box 149)
- Civics Education - Accompanying notes from countries (Box 150)
- Civics Education - National Version - New Zealand (Box 151)
- Minutes of IEA council meetings (Box 152)
- Studies in motivation (Box 153)
- Reading Comprehension - National Versions (Box 154)
- Empty envelopes, ready to be mailed, with names and address of different people: council members, NTO's, authors. The envelope's sender address: (Box 155)
- Institute For The Study Of International Problems In Education (Box 155)
- University of Stockholm (Box 155)
- Fack S-104 Stockholm 50, Sweden (Box 155)
- Postage stamp: Stockholm 50 (Box 155)
- Transparencies of one of the science instrument: "science practical population II" (Box 156)
- Proposal to the IEA for a study in the area of the role of the school in emotional and social development by John Raven / IEA/FA/1 late 1970s (Box 157)
- Letters between DR W B Dockrell Scottish Council for Research in Education about proposals on research into Affective Domain (Box 157)
- A letter from Wolf (Teachers College, 1980) [saying "not enthusiastic... the whole area is underdeveloped... the IEA made its reputation as an applied research organization... it is not a basic research outfit... going internationally seems highly immature... the proposal appears to be largely atheoretical... previous IEA work in related area-political and social attitudes in civic education was less than overwhelmingly successful. The IEA has a lot in its plate"] (Box 157)
- IEA Chairman Report: Jan 1986 (GA 26 minutes), April, 1985, Jan 1985, April 1984, December 1983 (25th anniversary), April 1983, Jan 1983, July 1982, Oct 1981, July 1981 (Box 157)
- Language and Instructions and School Achievement: (Box 157)
- Versions of research proposals from 1983, 1985 (Box 157)
- Research proposal on "The Use of First and Second Language in Primary Education", submitted to the world bank 1980, by Nadine Dutcher (Box 157)
- Look for Stacy Churchill, Canada? (Box 157)
- IEA Training Program (Box 158)
- Draft of proposal by Bloom "IEA Seminar on Reducing the Achievement Gap in Education" 1981 (Box 158)
- Invitations sent to: Korea, Indonesia, Thailand, India, Nigeria, Chile, Brazil, Swaziland, Malaysia, Sri Lanka, Israel, Kenya, Gambia, Ghana, Argentina, Mexico, Egypt, Tanzania (1979), Sweden, Finland, Australia, New Zealand, Canada Ontario, Hungary, Bonn FRG (1979 part b) (Box 158)
- Draft on Seminar on National Surveys of Literacy (Box 158)
- Proposed Training Program 1980 - 1985 (with details about previous program) (Box 158)
- South East Asia Training Seminar 1980 - 1982 (Box 158)
- Malaysia information kit (Box 158)
- Indonesia (Box 158)
- Malay (Box 158)
- Thailand (Box 158)
- Letters and reports from Ken Ross and others about the seminar (Box 158)
- Miscellaneous (Box 159)
- Miscellaneous (Box 160)
- IEA GA meetings papers, 1977, 1978, 1979, 1980 (Box 161)
- IEA GA meetings papers, 1984 (Singapore), 1983 (Netherlands) (Box 161)
- IEA, correspondence with national centers (Box 162)
- Sri-Lanka (1980) (Box 162)
- Swaziland (1979) (Box 162)
- Sweden (1986 - 1979) (Box 162)
- Switzerland (1986s) (Box 162)
- Trinidad (Box 162)
- Thailand (Box 162)
- Taipei China (Box 162)
- Item Bank (Box 162)
- Item Bank (Box 163)
- Documents and publications, folder about Rasch Scaling (Box 163)
- Transition from school to work, 1982s (Box 164)
- Letters and correspondence from different countries (Box 164)
- IEA (1980) (Box 165)
- Memos from NPT (Box 165)
- Memos in German from DFG (Box 165)
- Proposal on "evaluation of practical skills" by Lewy, Dave and TNP for IEA GA 1980 Finland (Box 165)
- Proposal on longitudinal study and follow up of IEA cohorts (Box 165)
- Proposal on Values (Box 165)
- Classroom environment 1982s (Box 165)
- Classroom environment, 1980s (Box 165)
- Classroom environment (Box 166)
- IPC Agenda 1984 (Box 166)
- Budgets, finance, papers in German (I think) (Box 166)
- Classroom environment - teaching for learning, various papers and documents (1980) (Box 166)
- Classroom Environment, instruments and manuals (Box 167)
- Classroom Environment, reports, reviews (Box 167)
- Classroom Environment, general (Box 167)
- Classroom Environment, proposal, budget and papers (Box 168)
- Classroom Environment, memos (Box 168)
- Classroom Environment, general correspondence A-G (Box 169)
- Classroom Environment, general correspondence H-L (Box 169)
- Classroom Environment, item analysis (Box 169)
- Research Proposal Classroom Environment (1980) 2 copies (Box 170)
- Classroom Environment - report of activities Sep 1979 - March 1980 by Tamar Levin, TAU (Box 170)
- Classroom Environment - Phase 1 The Correlational Study Thailand (1983) (Box 170)
- Classroom Environment, general correspondence M-Z (Box 170)
- IEA math study 1979 (Box 171)
- IEA math study 1979, French version of test (Box 171)
- Stack: IEA 2nd Math Study (Box 172)
- Stack: IEA 2nd Math Study, memos, funding, budget and proposal, newsletter and progress report (Box 172)
- Stack: IEA 2nd Math Study, 1980 - 1982 (Box 173)
- Stack: IEA 2nd Math Study, instruments, computer printouts etc' (Box 173)
- Stack: IEA 2nd Math Study (Box 174)
- Stack: IEA 2nd Math Study (Box 174)
- Stack: IEA 2nd Math Study, instruments (Box 175)
- Stack: IEA 2nd Math Study, 1985 (Box 175)
- Stack: IEA 2nd Math Study (Box 176)
- Stack: IEA 2nd Math Study, 1986 (Box 176)
- Stack: IEA 2nd Math Study, general (Box 177)
- Stack: IEA 2nd Math Study, general (Box 177)
- Stack: IEA 2nd Math Study (Box 178)
- Stack: IEA 2nd Math Study, correspondence about it (Box 178)
- Stack: IEA 2nd Math Study, 1984 (Box 179)
- Stack: IEA Science, countries [Zimbabwe] (Box 179)
- Second IEA Science Study (Box 180)
- IEA GA meetings minutes 1985 (Box 181)
- IEA Transition to Work proposal, 1984 (Box 181)
- IEA GA meetings minutes 1981-1982 (Box 181)
- IEA GA meetings minutes 1981 (Box 182)
- Correspondence with national centers (Box 183)
- Correspondence with national centers (Box 184)
- Correspondence with national centers (Box 185)
- Correspondence with national centers (Box 186)
- Correspondence with national centers (Box 187)
- Correspondence with national centers (Box 188)
- Correspondence with national centers 1979/1980 onwards (Box 189)
- NPT correspondence as chair of IEA, 1982 (Box 190)
- IEA Data bank, correspondence with ERIC and Repositories 1974 (Box 191)
- Stage 3 reports from national centers (1971-1972) [about implementation in each country and how problems were addressed] (Box 192)
- Ford Foundation 1972-1979 (Box 193)
- B-Documents 1972-1973. Paper: "An International Conference on Comparative Studies of Mathematics Curricula... Stability and change in Mathematics Curricula 1960-1980" (Box 193)
- IEA requests for publications, 1974 - (Box 194)
- IEA DATA Bank, requests, pending and in progress 1975 - (Box 195)
- International press conference, May 1973, May 1975 and June 1976 (Box 196)
- Costumes (Box 196)
- Pre-School education, international documents (Box 197)
- IEA 2nd Science Study, 1982 to XXXX (Box 197)
- IEA Item Bank Project, 1978 (Box 198)
- IEA Writing Study, 1980 (Box 198)
- IEA Standing Committee meeting, 1983 (Box 199)
- IEA 2nd Science Study, correspondence (Box 199)
- IEA Brochure News Letter, 1983 (Box 199)
- Minutes Of The IEA Standing Committee (1980) (Box 200)
- IEA GA meeting 1982, Canberra. Annual report of the projects (Box 201)
- IEA GA meeting 1982, Canberra. Correspondence with Malcolm Rosier, Keevs, NTP, GA members, Observers, Others (Box 201)
- IEA GA meeting 1982 (October), Toronto (Box 201)
- IEA GA meeting 1983, Enschede (Box 201)
- Proposal on Language of Instruction and School Achievement (1985) by Prof' Stacy Churchill (Box 202)
- Proposal on Language of Instruction and School Achievement (Box 202)
- Text on IEA: aims, organizational structure and working functions (Box 202)
- Text on IEA: governance, staff and operating procedures (Box 202)
- Correspondence from Purves 1982 (Box 202)
- Correspondence: application to membership in IEA from Kenya, Singapore (Box 202)
- IEA funding agencies and financial documents (Box 202)
- Prizes, press releases, information on publications, advertising. 1968 (Box 202)
- IEA 1978 Annotated Bibliography. 1982 (Box 203)
- 1980/1979 Brochure Contents (Box 203)
- Minutes of the IEA GA meetings (Box 204)
- Computer job printouts (white A3 paper) Start: 15 Maj (May??) 1974; End: Okt (October) 1974 (Box 205)
- Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) Time period: 1974 (Box 206)
- Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) (Box 207)
- Israel II Civics, between schools uni-variates population 2, Time: April 1973 (Box 207)
- Netherlands I / II / IV / Civics, between schools uni-variates, Time: April 1973 (Box 207)
- New-Zealand II / IV Civics, between schools uni-variates, Time: April 1973 (Box 207)
- Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) (Box 208)
- FRONV (Box 208)
- India, Hungary, France, Finland, FRG, Chile, Australia, Israel, Scotland, Netherlands, Japan, England, Italy (Box 208)
- Type of analysis: correlation matrices (Box 208)
- Botswana Manuel, different questionnaires, Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) (Box 209)
- PLMBOT 2, Jan 77, Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) (Box 209)
- PLMBOT 3, Jan 77, Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) (Box 209)
- Iran IV Civics, Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) (Box 209)
- Ireland Civics II / IV, Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) (Box 209)
- Ireland Civics I, Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) (Box 209)
- Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) Different Countries, Time: 18 February 1975 (Box 210)
- Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) Different Countries, Time: 02 November 1972 (Box 211)
- Various publications: US long-term economic growth prospects (1978), International Education Act of 1966 (Box 212)
- Blue Calendar and publication list (Box 212)
- Different papers from 1969 (Box 212)
- Documents on French as second language (Box 213)
- Envelopes with papers in unknown language (Box 213)
- Day file, 16/5/1970 - 26/7/1970 (Box 213)
- Day file, 27/7/1970-14/10/1970 (Box 213)
- Day file, 1/1/1970 - 26/2/1970 (Box 214)
- Documents 1964, National Case Study Questionnaire (Box 214)
- Intentions of the IEA project (Box 215)
- IEA documents (Box 215)
- T. Husen. Documents about the project 1966 (Box 216)
- Documents about the project 1966 (Box 216)
- Day file, 1/3/1970 - 14/5/1970 (Box 216)
- IEA list of documents. 1963s (Box 216)
- Tests from Sweden (?) (Box 217)
- IEA Diverse materials, including hypotheses (!) about the research questions (Box 217)
- IEA Documents A, 1967s (Box 217)
- Draft of a publication? (Box 218)
- IEA Documents B, 1967s (Box 218)
- IEA Diverse materials, including manuals, bubble sheet, national case study questioner (Box 218)
- Invoices 1971, Sweden (Box 219)
- Invoices 1972, Sweden (Box 219)
- Invoices 1971-1972, Sweden, dollar account (Box 220)
- Invoices 1972-1972, Sweden, dollar account (Box 220)
- Invoices 1971, Sweden, corona account (Box 221)
- Invoices 1971, Sweden, Belgium frank account (Box 221)
- Invoices 1971, Sweden, German Mark account (Box 221)
- Various publications (Box 222)
- Publications from Mexico (Box 222)
- IEA - International Project on the Evaluation of Educational Achievements, April 1963. UNESCO. Bulletin #2 (Box 223)
- IEA - International Project on the Evaluation of Educational Achievements, Feb 1964. UNESCO. Bulletin #3 (Box 223)
- IEA - International Project on the Evaluation of Educational Achievements, May 1964. UNESCO. Bulletin #4 (Box 223)
- IEA - International Project on the Evaluation of Educational Achievements. Phase I: International Study of Achievement in Mathematics a comparison of twelve countries (Box 223)
- Invoices: 1973, Sweden, corona account (Box 224)
- IEA-TR 31-50 1971: Six - Subject study? (Box 225)
- IEA TR 47 - pervading hypotheses [in the sense that they are of general interests to educational policy makers] (Box 225)
- Invoices 1972-1973 (Box 226)
- Invoices 1972-1973 (Box 226)
- Invoices 1972-1973 (Box 226)
- Budgets and grants 1971 (Box 227)
- Grants proposals (Box 227)
- Invoices (Box 227)
- Invoices (Box 227)
- IEA / UNESCO documents, [maybe tests in Swedish?] (Box 228)
- ETS developments, May 1964 (Box 228)
- National Case Study Questionnaire NCSQ 1971: Countries report and profile and correspondence (Box 229)
- Budget 1969 - 1970 (Box 229)
- Budget 1969 (Box 229)
- World Bank; correspondence with IEA and Mats Hultin - Senior Adviser Education Department (Box 229)
- Computer job printouts (Box 230)
- IEA Correspondence 1956 - 1966: editing the manuscript and making the organization (Box 231)
- ESL - report from different countries - Iran, Finland, UK etc'. Reaction to a given document with hypotheses and statements (Box 231)
- Teaching Behaviors and Student Achievement by Barak Rosenshine (logo: IEA, Stanford, Teachers College) (Box 231)
- Data Bank Manual (Box 231)
- Computer job printouts (Box 232)
- IEA mother tongue tests 1969 (2 copies) (Box 233)
- IEA Data Bank, users guide (Box 233)
- Manuals 1969 (Box 233)
- IEA, phase II, stage 2, questionnaires reprint Jan 1974 (2-3 copies) (Box 233)
- IEA Manual, phase 2 stage 2 (Box 234)
- Math tests (Box 234)
- Reading Comprehension (Box 234)
- Achievement in Math (Box 234)
- Science (Box 234)
- Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) (Box 235)
- Reports from the Reading test, Science test, different countries (Box 235)
- Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) (Box 236)
- Reports from the Civics test, different countries (Box 236)
- Time: April 1973, May 1975 (Box 236)
- IEA cross-tabs (Box 236)
- Computer job printouts (Box 237)
- Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) (Box 238)
- Front page say: CIVICS between schools uni-variates by country, Time: April 1973 (Box 238)
- Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) Different countries (Box 239)
- Large blue book titled: "IEA DATA BANK L" (Box 240)
- Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) of IEA six subject study (Box 240)
- Computer job printouts (Box 241)
- IEA Bureau meeting, Harvard Nov 10 1973 [seems to be a copy of Roy W. Phillips] (Box 242)
- IEA Bureau meeting, Stockholm 25-26 May 1973 [seems to be a copy of Roy W. Phillips] (Box 242)
- IEA Bureau meeting, 24-25 February 1973 [seems to be a copy of Roy W. Phillips] (Box 243)
- Collection of IEA documents from 1966-1968, including questionnaires. [maybe also belong to Roy W. Phillips] (Box 243)
- Collection of documents about English as Foreign Language, 1974 (Box 244)
- Documents not in English (Box 244)
- IEA, John Hall Letters (Box 244)
- IEA MALLAR MEDDEL, various documents from the late 1960s (Box 244)
- Documents and tests, [maybe in German] (Box 245)
- IEA English as Foreign Language, 1970 (Box 245)
- IEA Bulletin 1968 (Box 245)
- Reading comprehension, tests and questionnaires (Box 246)
- Six subject study, tests and questionnaires (Box 246)
- Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) of science, reading and literature study, Analysis type: regression, different countries, November 1972 (Box 247)
- Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) of listening study and test, different countries, April 1974 (Box 248)
- Computer job printouts, (white A3 paper) of reading study, Analysis type: regression, different countries, 1973 (Box 249)
- IEA - Six Subject Study, documentation (Box 250)
- Various IEA documents from 1963, case study Questionnaire (Box 250)
- Copy UNESCO report on education in the world, 1983 (Box 250)
- Data bank order forms (Box 251)
- IEA English as foreign language, October 1970. Questionnaire (Box 251)
- IEA Science, November 1969 (Box 251)
- IEA newsletter, 1986-10 (Box 251)
- IEA newsletter, 1982-1 (Box 251)
- IEA newsletter, 1985-7 (Box 251)
- IEA newsletter, 1984-6 (Box 251)
- Key to Six-Subject Data Bank Instrument (Box 251)
- Key to Six-Subject Data Bank Instrument, French Tests, 1974 (Box 251)
- IEA Science - responses to curriculum analysis binder (Box 252)
- Various documents 1969 with example of computerized answers cards (Box 252)
- IEA 2nd Math Study documents and computer codes (Box 253)
- STUDENTS, surveys and national documents (Box 253)
- Hungary, Six-subject study instruments (Box 254)
- IEA - SISS, meetings and documents (Box 255)
- IEA - SISS 1986 (not in English) (Box 256)
- IEA - SISS 1986 (not in English) (Box 256)
- IEA - SISS 1986, manuscript about comparison between USA and Japan (Box 257)
- SAMDRA, computer reports (Box 257)
- 1988/1989 (not in English) (Box 258)
- 1983 (math and stats) (Box 258)
- A Documents, 128-150, 1973, Harvard conference etc (Box 259)
- A Documents, 164 - 186 (Box 259)
- Sampling (seems to be in German with lists of students in classrooms 1982-1983.) (Box 260)
- Correspondence of Herman Wells (early 1970s - 1986) (Box 260)
- A Documents, 1-80, 1965 - 1971 [different discussion on methods: parents interview, longitudinal etc] (Box 261)
- A Documents, 81-111, proposals and discussion (Box 261)
- A Documents, 110-127 [very general] (Box 262)
- Various documents [about data files etc.] (Box 262)
- Correspondence 1969 from Neville P and Torsten (Box 263)
- IEA - stage 3 manuals 1970 (Box 263)
- Various documents [about data files etc., maybe a continuum from 262] (Box 263)
- Various documents, such as "Study of Guessing" (Box 264)
- Day File, Jan 1972 (Box 264)
- Day File, August - September 1971 (Box 264)
- Day File, Oct 1971 (Box 265)
- Accounting 1985 (computer printout) (Box 265)
- Complete population 1-2, 1983 (not in English, maybe Swedish) (Box 266)
- Complete population 3, 1983 (not in English, maybe Swedish) (Box 266)
- Reprints by the Author: document on "Remarks on the Execution of Research by Large Units" (Box 267)
- Reprints by the Author (Box 268)
- IEA data bank format (Box 269)
- IEA materials, 1980s (Box 269)
- Computer outputs (not sure what study, 1970s) (Box 270)
- IEA data bank freezer (not sure what study, 1970s) (Box 270)
- SPEC'S for regressions, Reading study (1971) (Box 271)
- Collection of journals on computing machinery and communication (1973s) (Box 271)
- Proposal for US commissioner on education (1966) (Box 272)
- Collection of science and chemistry, pretest report item (Box 272)
- "The comparative study of environmental policy" by David Vogel, UC-Berkley (Box 273)
- Civic education, pretest (Box 273)
- IEA CIVIC VOL I, Chapter III, 8/1972 (Box 273)
- IEA CIVIC, 4/1970 (Box 273)
- Civic education, pretest report item (Box 273)
- Computer printouts (Box 274)
- National Case Study Questioner (1971) (Box 275)
- Documents about instruments - general attitudes and descriptive measures (1967) (Box 275)
- Collection of national reports stage 2 and stage 3 (Box 275)
- Instrument for reading comprehension (Box 276)
- Science, pretest and item report (Box 276)
- Science, pretest and item report}1967 (Box 276)
- Computer reports 1968 (Box 277)
- Science, national centers reports (Box 277)
- Data Bank items (Box 277)
- old tapes before Oct 1974, computer printouts (Box 278)
- program FREEZER (Box 278)
- MATH Data Bank LISTS from NY (computer printout, 1975) (Box 279)
- IEA analyses (computer printout) (Box 279)
- F-A, various documents on regression models and usages of IEA data "Inequalities in the Allocation of Educational Resources" (Box 280)
- Bank account and invoices 1969-1970 (Box 280)
- Bank account and invoices 1970-1971 (Box 280)
- IEA stage 3 Data processing documents (letters from Judith T. about civics) (Box 281)
- Harwell subroutine library (computer program?) (Box 281)
- IEA programs details and source list, IEA Data Bank (Box 282)
- Bank account and invoices (Sweden) (Box 282)
- Bank account and invoices 1969 - 1970 (Box 283)
- Bank account and invoices 1971 (Box 283)
- Bank account and invoices 1970 (Box 283)
- Bank account and invoices 1970 (Box 283)
- Miscellany? (Box 284)
- Bank account and invoices 1970 (Box 285)
- Bank account and invoices 1969 - 1970 (Box 285)
- Bank account and invoices 1969 (Box 286)
- Collection of IEA manuals (Box 287)
- Publication: Citations of the IEA studies: A listing (1981) (Box 287)
- IEA "Fact Book" 1970 (2 copies) (Box 287)
- Correspondence with ACER and others mid 1980s (Box 288)
- UNESCO and IEA PROV II: (Box 288)
- International Math Test Advanced Form (Box 288)
- Computer reports (Box 288)
- International Math Test (Box 288)
- Publication: IEA Phase II Stage 2 Word Knowledge, Dec 1968 (Box 289)
- Books about Universities in 2000s (Box 290)
- Large maps with frequency data of different questionnaires (Box 290)
- Large maps with frequency data of different questionnaires [maybe for Teacher Reading Comprehension] (Box 291)
- Financial correspondence, early 1970s (Box 291)
- USA, Finland, Poland, Netherland - Math questionnaire (Box 292)
- Science POP II, subtest 3,4 (questionnaire) (Box 292)
- Science POP II, subtest 7,8 (Box 293)
- Science POP IV, subtest 1,2,3,4 (Box 293)
- IEA literature study, booklets and proposed text (Box 294)
- IEA ESL study, booklets and more? (Box 294)
- Chicago University, June 1967 "Illustrative test items for assessing attainment of the objective of science teaching" (Box 295)
- Minutes and meetings 1971 (Box 295)
- Daily File, March 1973 (Box 295)
- IEA Booklet 1970 - Finland? (Box 295)
- IEA Hamburg 1-2 1968 (Box 296)
- IEA Korrespondence/correspondence, 1965-1964 (Box 297)
- IEA Korrespondence/correspondence, 1966 (Box 297)
- IEA Korrespondence/correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 297)
- IEA Korrespondence/correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 298)
- IEA Korrespondence/correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 299)
- IEA Korrespondence/correspondence, 1965-1966 with USA (Box 299)
- Reading comprehension, Literature, Science (Husen): chapters and reports on different studies (Box 300)
- Letters 1962 - 1965 (Box 301)
- IEA Council Meeting, Frankfort 1972 [it seems to be Husen's copy] (Box 302)
- TR documents 108 - 126, 1972 (Box 302)
- TR documents 127 - 143, 1972 (Box 303)
- IEA final reports and publications 1973 (Box 303)
- Gilbert Peaker correspondence 1972 (Box 304)
- Peaker's comment on??? 1973 (Box 304)
- Gilbert Peaker correspondence 1973 (Box 305)
- Gilbert Peaker correspondence 1967 - 1968 (Box 306)
- Gilbert Peaker's articles (Box 306)
- Super Monograph mid 1970s (Box 307)
- Contracts with authors and publication rights (Box 307)
- Bank account and invoices?? (Box 308)
- English and French documents 1972 [reports on progress and dispatches] (Box 308)
- Stage 3 questionnaire (Box 309)
- Publication: IEA phase II Stage 2, French as foreign language, English as Foreign Language, civic education, attitude and descriptive scales, Feb 1969 (Box 310)